DAVID BOGAERTS

■ dbogaerts@gmail.com • https://bogey1185.github.io/portfolio/ • Deerfield. Illinois in /in/david-bogaerts • bogey1185

Summary

I am a developer with a passion for the creation of things that make peoples' lives easier and more enjoyable. As a former attorney, I developed a relentless work ethic and careful attention to detail that served me well in my coding education, and I continue to put these skills to use as I develop elegant and effective web applications.

Technical Experience

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive

Chicago, Illinois Dec. 2018 to Mar. 2019

Full-stack web development student at an intensive, thirteen-week program focused on common best practices in product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, test-driven development, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects including those projects listed below.

Projects

LeaseGuard

Utility for renters and landlords allowing documentation of property damage. (React with Express API)

Pollster

Custom social polling application. (Fullstack Python)

CrowdTales

Application that crowd-sources content for books and short stories. (React with Python Flask API)

Other Relevant Experience

Langhenry, Gillen, Lundquist & Johnson LLC . Associate Attorney

May 2016 to Oct.

Handled all aspects of litigation from a defense perspective on complex litigation matters. Utilized critical thinking skills and close attention to detail in order to quickly and effectively learn new areas of law, analyze new cases, and provide clients a vigorous defense.

Pullano Law Offices · Associate Attorney

Jan. 2015 to Apr. 2016

Associate attorney for a small plaintiff-oriented litigation firm.

18th Judicial Circuit of DuPage County · Staff Attorney Mar. 2013 to Jan. 2015 Utilized quick and efficient research skills to serve the varied needs of 40+ Judges in DuPage County on a wide variety of criminal and civil matters.

Skills

LANGUAGES/DATABASES

HTML

CSS

Javascript

Python 3

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES

JOuery

Velocity.js

Express.is

React.is

Flask

AJAX

Bootstrap

Education

General Assembly Dec. 2018 to Mar. 2019 Web Development Immersive 2019

Valparaiso Universitv School of Law

Juris Doctor 2012 Graduated with distinction,

Magna Cum Laude

Cumulative GPA: 3.56/4.0

Class Rank: 11/153

Elmhurst College Aug. 2004 to June 2008

BA Music Business 2008 Graduated with distinction,

Magna Cum Laude Cumulative GPA: 3.8/4.0